Daniel Correa

Paraprofessional

Personal Info

Address

114 Radcliff Place Morganville, NJ 07751

Phone

7327782098

E-mail

dancorrea3@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/danielcorrea-91b44918/

Date of birth

1986-05-30

Place of birth

Bronx, NY

Skills

When necessary, instructing between 2-6 autism high school students simultaneously

Implement behavior charts and data collection sheets for various behaviors and multiple students for school behaviorist

Paraprofessional with +3 years of experience in a high school level, special education environment. Outgoing and detail-oriented, I am proficient at building and maintaining professional relationships with both teaching/paraprofessional staff and autism program students. AA in Education to be completed by September 2017.

Experience

2012-02 -**Paraprofessional**

present

Monmouth-Ocean Education Services Commission

- -Experience working with students on the Autism Spectrum
- -Assisted students with various challenging physical/intellectual needs
- -Recording data under the direction of the teacher and/or behaviorist
- -Experienced with social skill development and behavior modification
- -Works with multiple Autism Spectrum students on a daily basis

Audio Visual Coordinator 2011-05 -

Zarephath Christian Church

Samson Jr's Rent 2 Own

2012-02

- -Recruited, trained and managed members of the Audio/Visual Media Team
- -Maintained integrity of sound field during performance
- -Trained new and existing volunteers
- -Drafted monthly schedules for media team
- -Set up and operate audiovisual equipment such as cameras, film, slide projectors, and recording/PA equipment

2012-02 -**Credit Specialist**

2012-06

-Created, maintained, and organized files for new and current clients; following up with preliminary warm and cold applicants.

-Assessed training needs through surveys, interviews with employees, focus groups and consultation with managers

Education

2008-04 present

Brookdale Community College, Education, AA

(Expected graduation date: 09/2017) Studied topics such as: developmental disability, children with multiple/severe physical and/or intellectual disabilities, behavior disorders, history and laws of special education, special need categories, intelligence and classification, gifted/talented students and Inclusion classrooms.

2004-01 -

School of Audio Engineering, Audio Recording Technology

2006-01

Studied topics such as: studio equipment protocols, musical editing, musical production, live-sound engineering and recording, acoustics, electrical engineering, and studio operation techniques.

Volunteer Work

2016-09 -**Bible Teacher**

present

Study Group

- -Provide leadership and mentorship for local college student group
- -Create and teach weekly lessons to group of approximately 12